Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
David Mendenhall: Hello, friends.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello, adventurers.
David Mendenhall: Wade, are you joining us?
Wade Brown: Legends, and Wade.
David Mendenhall: Friends of the Maid. Yeah, maybe.
Wade Brown: No, that's fair.
David Mendenhall: Like you're in a low light situation. Oh, there you go.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah. Now I'm just, there's Vaseline all over the lens. There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: oh okay all right let me just see if i can get gary
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so uh, Dave?
UNKNOWN: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, your peculiar take on adventuring gold, or cardins, rather, peculiar approach. Vukradin did. Vukradin did, right. You have to understand that the entire economy of the area hinges on adventurers.
David Mendenhall: It could prove problematic in
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, as attracted the attention of a group of people.
David Mendenhall: Oh, really? Oh, I like this development. We'll have to see how that goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so, so, so, so there were
David Mendenhall: and others who believe in organic fair trade gold.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I would say others would believe. I wouldn't go that far. It's a big world. I'm sure we could find some species.
David Mendenhall: and some other fellow hippie adventurers who believe in Vukradin's warped sense of morality.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, I'm thinking Paladins.
David Mendenhall: Maybe. I don't know. I've seen plenty of Paladins who just take the gold.
Kostadis Roussos: You've seen one paladin who just takes the gold.
David Mendenhall: I think I saw one paladin who, like, tried to become evil on purpose for, like, to gain extra power. That was pretty awful.
Kostadis Roussos: What is the paladin?
David Mendenhall: Libyade's character.
Kostadis Roussos: oh no he wasn't a paladin then he was a uh he was a rogue
David Mendenhall: Oh, he's a rogue? Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, the Paladin was in the drow adventure.
David Mendenhall: Paladin was back in the Drowned Bunch? God, that's so long ago.
Kostadis Roussos: Bayard. Bayard.
David Mendenhall: Okay. Anyway...
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so I have to admit that this weekend I was doing a triathlon.
David Mendenhall: I saw that, yeah, Escape from Alcatraz.
Kostadis Roussos: Escape from Alcatraz
David Mendenhall: Second time! Congratulations!
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you, thank you, and as a result I did not have time to write a summary.
David Mendenhall: I did not have time to do a triathlon.
Kostadis Roussos: So.
David Mendenhall: Cary.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye
Gary Young: One second.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. And then today, I have a real job now, like my previous, you know, year where I was doing nothing.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And as a result, I didn't even have time to, like, anyway, I did not have time this week, so I apologize. Cool. I have to do the boring conventional thing of trying to remember what happened.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Also, does it not generate an AI summary? I think it does. Oh, it did. It does. So that was everybody's week.
Wade Brown: I'm in hell.
Gary Young: Well, yeah.
David Mendenhall: You're back from India. Congratulations. You made it back.
Gary Young: Sorry, he was saying something more serious.
Kostadis Roussos: Why are you in hell?
Wade Brown: Oh, it's not serious. It's just everything I basically left Roku for is like in spades here. We're now on like four or five pre-meetings before I can even get hardware in my hands.
Kostadis Roussos: Can I just say something? Dave earned that. It's so good.
David Mendenhall: I NEVER MADE YOU GO TO F-
Kostadis Roussos: Did you do D-Dave, Dave?
David Mendenhall: Never once did I do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Who didn't? Who didn't?
David Mendenhall: I did not.
Kostadis Roussos: Other people did. You can savor this moment. Savor it. You are allowed to savor it. Wade, thank you for sharing.
Wade Brown: I need to come up with every possible eventuality in what is essentially a task of kernel driver debug like I don't know how to plan my next three months around I'm going to look for the bugs in the kernel drivers and I'm going to fix them but they want that and I won't get hardware
David Mendenhall: This is where ChatGPT can help you a lot.
Wade Brown: No, this is where I just quit.
David Mendenhall: Hound,
Wade Brown: I'm just a contractor, what are they gonna do, fire me?
David Mendenhall: If you'd be interested in being a virtual machinist at Roku, I had somebody quit today and I have an opening.
Wade Brown: A virtual machinist.
David Mendenhall: and many more.
Wade Brown: What is that?
David Mendenhall: I suspect you'd like to integrate Hermes into the OS?
Wade Brown: Probably not.
David Mendenhall: Well, go look up what it is and then you can think about it.
Wade Brown: Yeah... Hermes?
Kostadis Roussos: How about this? You wouldn't have to attend meetings.
Wade Brown: What's the problem? I like doing work, but it's just, it's all meetings, wall-to-wall meetings, and I can't do shit. And they're like, well, bill hours and do something. Like, there's nothing to do.
Kostadis Roussos: So the problem is that you want to get stuff done, and then there's a whole army of people whose job it is to measure that you're doing stuff.
Wade Brown: I know oh dude these meetings are insane it's two engineers and eight managers like it's it's not an exaggeration it's me and the FPGA guy and 8 p.m types it's fucking nuts
David Mendenhall: I can promise you, you will not have 8 p.m. times. Let's play a game, because I've had a long day. Let's play a game.
Gary Young: I passed the project manager with building out the plan for the testing.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so I dumped the AI summary so that folks can remember what happened last week.
David Mendenhall: I remember what happened. We cleared out that previous dungeon and avoided the obvious trap and left it for the dwarves who are now dead.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I got conked out by an Osher jelly, but, uh, perhaps a little cleric brought me back up.
Gary Young: And then for some reason there was like a dagger in our inventory. It's great.
David Mendenhall: Crodden was very unhappy to see that when he looked today.
Wade Brown: Krogan can get his panties out of a bunch. Be more pragmatic.
David Mendenhall: He has definitely not learned pragmatism yet.
Wade Brown: He's too young. He's an idealist.
David Mendenhall: See now, there's always the character arc. We'll see.
Wade Brown: Oh, I like it. It gives me room to, you know, try to shepherd him out of his, you know, shitheaded teenage days.
David Mendenhall: Maybe you could roll for initiative.
Wade Brown: Are we at a... We are, indeed. Yes, we are. I swear I had the character sheet open. Where'd it go?
Gary Young: So Dave, you updated the spreadsheet incorrectly.
David Mendenhall: I'm sorry, what did I do?
Gary Young: You need the blood money item section, not just the blood money money.
David Mendenhall: That actually did occur to me.
Gary Young: Feel free to go ahead. Or, you know, like an Is Blood Money column.
David Mendenhall: I also considered that I am I'm so glad that we are aligned on this objective drow
Gary Young: Alright, we're gonna do Is Blood Money.
David Mendenhall: All right, his blood bones. The Boolean.
Kostadis Roussos: I have to decide, you know, like, what is, what is, what is, um, Valphine thinking here? Well, probably, how come the drow haven't conquered the overbrighters and slaughtered them all and made them slaves of the under...
David Mendenhall: Did you say in the last week that these are the bizarre machinations of surface dwellers?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but yeah, like at this point in time, I'm just thinking she's probably thinking that, you know, given how effete you were.
Gary Young: So keep in mind that she's not actually evil.
Kostadis Roussos: She's a drow! She's a drowser.
David Mendenhall: Blood. I love it. A full-on variable. Can we make like a T and F? And I guess these, I guess he believes these gemstones are F. So we'll go with F on that one.
Wade Brown: Can we do like a highlighting in Excel? Or not Excel, whatever, you know, to put a red tint on anything that's got true in that column.
Gary Young: i'm sure we could write a little bit of a javascript we're gonna have to have two summary columns uh it's two sub columns i'll work on it
Kostadis Roussos: Okinawa
David Mendenhall: Oh, God.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so clearly, I just want to say something.
David Mendenhall: I have to say, I'm having more fun already than I was at the end of Stormkicks. Things are going well.
Kostadis Roussos: well yeah we're full of potential right now yeah you know it was a different era all right okay all right let me go to the initiative
David Mendenhall: Orc, Orc, Orc
Kostadis Roussos: Did I roll initiative? Yes. I have numbers. I am sorting. Yeah, that's the wrong sort.
David Mendenhall: Upside down, sorry
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Vukradin, you are up first.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Jesus.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, is it... Hold on, hold on,
David Mendenhall: Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, Vukradin. How do I pronounce your name? Is it Vukradin, Vukradin, Vukradin?
David Mendenhall: I think Vukradin.
Wade Brown: Or V-Dog, just call him V-Dog.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me ask you a question. Does anyone other than your mother and your stalwart fans call you Vukrad? And doesn't anybody use a nickname like Din or Krod or Vuk?
David Mendenhall: I'm a serious musician I use my name I don't know what you think is going on here Neverember, Mooncrowding will be fine, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Do your friends call you Cassidophorium? Yes. Are they your friends? No.
David Mendenhall: The answer is what, friends?
Kostadis Roussos: Are they your friends?
David Mendenhall: No.
Wade Brown: For what it's worth, we can barely see the orcs. We can see maybe like two of them. The rest are kind of up here in the fog of war.
David Mendenhall: I'm going first. This is very bad for the party that I'm going first. I would like to parlay with the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Do you actually walk up to them and say, "I wish to parlay"?
David Mendenhall: Sadly, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well...
Wade Brown: Oh, that boy's gonna get himself killed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, well, the orcs kind of say, the orcs are kind of like, cool, he's a dumbass. Actually, what they really say is, he recognizes our rights to this territory and is offering himself in sacrifice.
David Mendenhall: Sacrifice? No, I just wanted to talk. What is going? Why are you guys here? Like, did you need something? Do you need help? Like, are you looking for a place to stay? Like, are you hungry?
Wade Brown: Do you offer to fluff their pillows while you're at it?
David Mendenhall: I've never encountered orcs before. I'm very confused.
Kostadis Roussos: actually it's worse than that you have encountered orcs before but they were in um which we'll call it um storm kings no no no they were they were in a neverwinter and they were civilized
David Mendenhall: Oh, even better. There he is. Now I'm even doubly confused. He came and listened to my music.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah
David Mendenhall: Do you need me to play for you? I don't have my piano with me, but I have a trumpet.
Gary Young: You said a trumpet?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, a trumpet.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: I also have a clarinet. Would you prefer that? Do you want the reeded instrument or just the brass?
Wade Brown: So I don't understand any of this, right? He's speaking in Orc.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see.
Wade Brown: Clarinet seems more appropriate for that.
Kostadis Roussos: Do they speak Common and Orc?
David Mendenhall: Common.
Kostadis Roussos: all right so um all right so he uh moves over here
David Mendenhall: and Waxmeat.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Orc number one. Sorry. Orc number one kind of is like, What? Well, if you're going to give us a bonus round, we're going to take advantage of it. And he reaches with his greataxe and effin' misses, proving that God loves fools and sinners.
David Mendenhall: Alright, you missed. Great. Alright, the battle is joined then. Alright, Soma, don't be an idiot like me.
Wade Brown: You got lucky, kiddo.
David Mendenhall: He's dead.
Kostadis Roussos: This is where one of you remembers that there were Orc tribes that were coming down from the north.
David Mendenhall: We were told this by, like, the mayor of the town or something.
Kostadis Roussos: No, the innkeeper.
David Mendenhall: The Innkeeper. All right.
Wade Brown: All right, we're going to go ahead and cast Ice Knife on number three.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Wade Brown: Let's see. Actually, how high up are they? This is an incline, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, 20 feet.
Wade Brown: Okay, so theoretically, if I thorn-whipped a guy down, would he end up prone and take damage on the way down?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I guess so.
Wade Brown: Alright, then maybe that's what we do. We're just gonna thorn whip number two and drag him down.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what's the saving throw, or is it a two-hit?
Wade Brown: that's me five points
David Mendenhall: Twenty-two hits.
Kostadis Roussos: Yup.
Wade Brown: It's a hit. He falls down. Yeah, he gets dragged. Let's see. On a hit, the target takes 1d6, and then pull it 10 feet closer, which means he tumbles down the hill. I assume that knocks him prone or something.
David Mendenhall: You should bring him another five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm assuming this was 20 feet down.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I see, I see, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: right okay um so uh does he take fall damage
Wade Brown: At the very least, he should be prone or something.
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's definitely prone. I'm saying, I'm trying to decide if he takes fall damage because he was rolled down. Does he take prone damage? Does he take fall damage? Takes 1d6 worth of fall damage. How about that? That's a good enough. That works. Doesn't take the full 2d6. That's what I was trying to decide.
Wade Brown: Alright, he takes one more!
Kostadis Roussos: So, six points of damage.
Wade Brown: Six points on Orc number two. The important thing is he is CC'd. Init bonus, somebody already got him, good, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, who's next?
David Mendenhall: Work 4
Kostadis Roussos: Or four, is that what I heard?
Wade Brown: I heard our core.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm currently futzing with technology. That is not a good thing for me to be doing. I should be focused on playing and not on, you know, goofing off with technology. Because we all know that technology is in fact the source of all problems in modern society.
Wade Brown: No, it's PMs.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, since we have none here anymore, I suppose we could say that. Alright, so you did that. What does number four do? Okay. He can move, so he goes one, goes one, two, three, and it's like, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: and he will attack Vukradin again. Why? Because he happens to be closest.
Wade Brown: I mean, he did rush up into the front.
Kostadis Roussos: yeah he did so it's it's not it's not my fault uh except i forgot to roll to hit 18 you take 12 points of damage Damage Recruiting.
David Mendenhall: I am unconscious.
Kostadis Roussos: You are unconscious.
David Mendenhall: Let me do my death save.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, who's next?
David Mendenhall: I failed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Gary Young: I think it's me
David Mendenhall: It's going to be a very painful lesson that I learned.
Wade Brown: Well, maybe you won't learn anything, you'll just be dead.
David Mendenhall: I'll just be dead.
Gary Young: Alright, we'll go with Heal the Word, Healing Word, and then Sacred Flame.
David Mendenhall: You got 11 on a healing word? I didn't even know it could be that powerful. I thought it was like a d4. It's 2d4.
Gary Young: I believe I have Out.
Wade Brown: It says 2d4 plus 3 and he double crit.
David Mendenhall: Wow, nice. All right, so I have nine hit points. Thank you.
Gary Young: I ended up one point in Sacred Flame. Up to whom? We're going to go with... Actually, that's a good question. Hold on, prone condition. Why is Brewbarry injured? Then we do a long rest.
David Mendenhall: Long Rested, yeah, yeah.
Wade Brown: I didn't reset everything.
Gary Young: Well, uh, at any rate, um, it doesn't matter who I'm doing it on, so, uh, it will be on... Four. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Are you raging?
Gary Young: It is Brewbarry's turn next.
Wade Brown: Did we skip the prone guy?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah. Yeah, I didn't get. Yeah, the prone guy.
Wade Brown: I should have gone before the cleric.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, we'll...
Gary Young: Orkutu? Yes. Oh, yeah, you're right. Orkutu.
Wade Brown: His only action is stand up, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he can, prone, the prone condition, you can remove the prone condition by reducing your move rate by 15. Oh, okay. Vukredin would still be dead, so move Brewbarry. I'll just do, can I just do the Orc after Brewbarry? How about that? Yeah, that's fine. Alright, let's go.
Gary Young: It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry, go.
Gary Young: GO SMASH
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay.
Gary Young: But he doesn't have to be that close. He can be like here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Let's say...
Kostadis Roussos: And since he was knocked prone, you do have advantage on him. So roll again. You missed the 12 missed.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade Brown: D20 plus 5
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit. Seven points of damage.
Gary Young: On number two.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Which would... Put him at two hit points. I'll kill him. Nope. Yeah. By the way, did one of the orcs make a saving throw on Sacred Flame for one hit point?
Kostadis Roussos: yeah number four made us oh i didn't roll that number four it was the guy i don't know why he was moved all right i'm assuming uh what was your sacred flame oh yes you made your saving throw one one hit point made his hit
Gary Young: Okay, done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so this Orc... Okay, what does this Orc do? He just got whacked by Brewbarry, so he charges at Brewbarry. By the way, what does the cleave action do?
Gary Young: Oh, that's a good question. Cleave. Once per turn, if I hit a creature with a melee attack, I can make another melee attack against a second creature within 5 heat.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so do your second attack.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Prismulia, number one.
Gary Young: That is a hit. The second creature takes a halberd's damage but without ability modifier. So, not this, it would be... That would be a 9 damage.
Wade Brown: There's just been nine, yeah.
Gary Young: Line Damage on 1.
Wade Brown: On one. Alright.
Gary Young: That's useful. I should, like, actually do that. Yes. All right. So I believe you said that two was leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, he was advancing to you.
Gary Young: That's correct. He's leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, fair. Okay, what happens in that case?
Gary Young: That means that I get an attack of opportunity, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, fair enough, fair enough. Ah!
Gary Young: Uh, so that's an 18 to hit.
Wade Brown: If you have at least a plus three, you can't not kill him.
Gary Young: Alright, he dies.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Well done.
Kostadis Roussos: all right oh and i forgot to rage all right what would orc 3 did everybody's now decided for crudine as a loser who can't add much value
Wade Brown: He is a bard.
David Mendenhall: Kill them again.
Gary Young: So did anyone notice that Valphine is Yo?
David Mendenhall: I saw that.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's the texture on the map, isn't it? Yeah, it's supposed to say Canyon. So when your character's over it, it kind of goes in the background.
Wade Brown: It's weird that that's on the top layer, anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: I put it on the top layer it's uh it means that it's not it means that I can put these symbols on where they are and they will show regardless of whether you've discovered it or not otherwise if you put in the other layers and you don't have lighting you can't you can't see it so they had this new foreground layer that lets me do that um since this is causing people how about that okay all right It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I know, I know, but, you know, it was like, I was kind of annoyed by it, and so you guys brought it up, and I said, okay, it's not, I'm not going to look weird by being annoyed. Alright, okay, so, uh, he attacks with his greataxe.
Gary Young: I'm Valphine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: All right. AC 17.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, ho, ho, ho.
Wade Brown: One away from a crit at least.
Kostadis Roussos: for eight points of damage all right i'll take it all right down to two all right Vukradin
David Mendenhall: Alright, he understands now that he's fighting for his life here.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he not want to sit there and write a sonnet first?
David Mendenhall: He wants to live.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: He does not have a death wish. He is not.
Wade Brown: He's not late-stage Orsik. He's not Orsik.
David Mendenhall: Three damage on number one, and then we'll attack again, and misses with the second attack, that's a shame, alright.
Wade Brown: Yeah, that means he gets to hit back.
Kostadis Roussos: all right number one kind of notices that you hit him so he's like surprised he's like you you got he's like it's kind of like and he hit does he hit
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and he swings his greataxe and knocks me out again.
David Mendenhall: Wow. God, I am not designed for tanking.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no.
David Mendenhall: Okay, I think I'm learning my lesson on this one. Alright, Soma, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: You've learned a valuable lesson.
David Mendenhall: I am definitely learning things why they wanted to fight me I don't know but they wanted to fight me all right I made my destiny
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so much.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah, uh, I don't know. We'll just, uh, thorn whip him again, he should die from that, right? Actually, no, Poison Spray, that can do 1d12.
Kostadis Roussos: What's the range of that?
Wade Brown: 30 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so it's a target.
Wade Brown: yeah it's target at uh number one yeah
Kostadis Roussos: Number one guys.
Wade Brown: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: guys all right um orc number four all right hold on let's get rid of let's get nobody we aren't you folks aren't doing their jobs getting rid of the orc so we're down two and four okay i got i got rid of it i got rid of it Okay
David Mendenhall: So, that as well.
Gary Young: Forrestal up, three and four are up, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, a battle is not lost, they think to themselves. It can kill Valfi and it becomes two-on-two, so.
Gary Young: Yeah, that's not gonna help.
Wade Brown: Ignore the damage, dealers!
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's not a hit. No, that's not a hit. Okay. Brubit, Valphine, you're up.
Gary Young: I'll see you.
Kostadis Roussos: Disengage is a good strategy.
Gary Young: Nah. Nah. I'm enjoying the pain here.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I was worried you were going to say, all right?
Gary Young: Let's see, they both are at full hit points, okay. Then I'll just attack four, and then we'll go with just a regular mace attack.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss. Okay. Alright. Uh... Brew... Brewbarry.
Gary Young: pro-variable attack from here
David Mendenhall: We'll have the owl bird. That is neat.
Gary Young: We can just leave again.
Kostadis Roussos: That was a hit for seven points of damage on number three. All right, I marked it.
Gary Young: and then Cleave.
Kostadis Roussos: that is how much damage it's like six oh hold on hold on hold on when you're raging you also add a certain number of points to your damage which i don't think about it does by default
Gary Young: Yeah, but I forgot to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: Again?
Gary Young: I mean, I guess I could rage right now. This is my turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
David Mendenhall: Go ahead and do it, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
UNKNOWN: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I almost feel that if Vukradin goes down, you automatically rage.
Gary Young: Not my long friend.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, when Vucurdean goes down, I'll automatically rage, that's right. You're like, I think you automatically rage because, like, this is, you know, he's your, he's the musical genius of your life. Alright, so you had, the first attack was 9 points of damage. So you got a plus, you got a plus 2 to fix that.
Kostadis Roussos: And the second attack is you get eight points of damage.
Gary Young: All right, rage bonus damage. What is my rage bonus damage again?
Kostadis Roussos: It's plus two, I looked it up last time. If you go to the 2024 D&D rules under barbarian tables, it goes plus two, it's your proficiency bonus until a particular level, and then it goes to plus three, but it does not reach the same max as your proficiency, so it doesn't go to plus five.
Speaker 7: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty. Orc number 6. Okay, so Orc 3 suddenly realizes, hmm, is he clever enough to figure this out?
David Mendenhall: No
Kostadis Roussos: Yes he is!
David Mendenhall: Targets.
Kostadis Roussos: yeah no he he doesn't advance he throws his uh javelin at Brewbarry yeah
Gary Young: Okay, that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: And he hits and he starts and he says awful things about Uthgardtian barbarians and, you know, questions the circumstances of their birth and, you know, all that sort of stuff.
Gary Young: I will shrug off 5 damage worth of it.
David Mendenhall: Wow. That is impressive.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Vukradin. That's safe.
David Mendenhall: that's a pretty sad combat for me you're a bard failed
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: I like how you guys like stopped standing me up. That's appropriate. It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: It's almost done.
Wade Brown: Yeah, he goes
David Mendenhall: Omai, you're up.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah, we're going to, we're probably going to take down Valphine in the fracas, but I don't know how much longer we got, so we're going to ice knife the guy in the back and it'll probably shard onto everyone.
David Mendenhall: Nice, do it.
Wade Brown: Oh, nope, I just completely whiffed. Excellent.
David Mendenhall: No, no, but does it, like... There's still area damage, though, right?
Wade Brown: Let me check, yeah, uh, on hits, if you're seeing, hit or miss, the shard then explodes, each creature within 5 feet must succeed, dex saving throw or take 2d6.
Kostadis Roussos: including Valphine.
David Mendenhall: Including Valphine.
Wade Brown: I know
Kostadis Roussos: Two hit points.
David Mendenhall: Just make your deck save, you'll be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, actually, she won't. They'd already rolled the cold damage, it was seven.
Wade Brown: Oh, right, right, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: I failed my dex save. So you are knocked out.
Wade Brown: Yes, but, so is, let's see, Orc number one should be dead unless he makes his save. Actually, they'd both be dead unless they make their saves.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what's the saving throw?
Wade Brown: X-13.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, D20, 2d20. One makes it, unless... both might make it.
Wade Brown: It's a 13, right?
David Mendenhall: I like that the end result of your attack is that you killed your ally and did no further damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, they all made it.
David Mendenhall: Well, no.
Wade Brown: Well done!
Gary Young: So do I do a death save now? So I do a death save right now?
David Mendenhall: Yes, you do. I'm sorry, Valphine.
UNKNOWN: Hook
Gary Young: The tactical brilliance of this crew is...
Kostadis Roussos: Look, we're not a-
David Mendenhall: Shatter, it'll get better.
Wade Brown: We just met each other on the road, right?
David Mendenhall: Like we got the ogres quite effectively.
Kostadis Roussos: You take D6 plus 3 damage. You take 5 points of damage, Brewbarry, but that's halved because you're raging, so you're down to 2 points. You're down 2 points.
David Mendenhall: And the time.
Gary Young: Oh, I take half because I take less when you're then I then I probably took zero from the last attack
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Gary Young: Alright, so you're saying I take two now?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Okay. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Valphine, second death save
Kostadis Roussos: No, Vukradin.
David Mendenhall: Well, our team's up. Okay, you're at plus-minus.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright? Brewbarry, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Can you please save the party?
Wade Brown: Yeah, sorry man. I'm still new to this whole magic thing.
Gary Young: Brewbarry,
David Mendenhall: Boomerang
Gary Young: Well, we can just attack both of them with Halberd again.
David Mendenhall: That sounds like a good plan. That's a hit.
Gary Young: All right.
Wade Brown: And that is another hit.
David Mendenhall: That can be two counts, yeah.
Gary Young: I don't know
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, let's make sure.
Wade Brown: Seven and seven.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 and 9
Wade Brown: No, it's 9 and... Oh, because you're forgetting your plus 2, yeah.
David Mendenhall: I only have seven and six hit points.
Gary Young: That's 9 and 9, I think, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, they are all dead. Alright, I presume Brewbarry has to decide whether he's going to kill Sobob, but maybe he doesn't?
David Mendenhall: I assume Brewbarry is going to help Vukradin, his musician friend, right?
Kostadis Roussos: I think so yeah and Soma you're going to help Valphine
Wade Brown: I mean, absolutely, I'm going to help them up. Kind of sheepishly.
Gary Young: So are we doing like medicine checks? Is that how this works again?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm assuming since the combat is over you're able to stabilize everybody.
Gary Young: Oh, okay. Yeah, sure, all right.
Kostadis Roussos: If it, yes, right.
David Mendenhall: Long rest, everybody. Maybe we could go back in the Bruin and lick our wounds and talk about what the hell had just happened.
Gary Young: Wait, hold on. Yeah, go ahead and do that. And I'll urge the bodies.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay. Yeah, I'll head on over. Yeah, that sounds good.
Wade Brown: Come on, Vukradin, let's get you back somewhere where you can perform.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade Brown: Tell tales of your brush with death.
Gary Young: So he needs to enjoy the-
David Mendenhall: Orcs slaughtered us. Slaughtered us. Yes, it was the orcs. And the orcs slaughtered us.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so yeah, okay, so then, okay, so...
Gary Young: I assume there's nothing of value on the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I didn't say that.
Gary Young: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I just need to friggin' find something.
Wade Brown: They're suspiciously dexterous, so you know, maybe they got something there.
Kostadis Roussos: There you go.
Kostadis Roussos: They've got a broken haddax, a javelin, and some hide armor.
Wade Brown: Harbour.
Kostadis Roussos: Hide Armour, okay. You know, you could pick up the Battle Axes and try to sell them. For Battle Axes? Yep.
Wade Brown: Are they Blood Money Battle Axes?
David Mendenhall: Definitely. They're absolutely stolen.
Wade Brown: But you're not aware that this happened.
David Mendenhall: As soon as I see them hit the party inventory, I will be.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, hold on, Brewbarry could, I mean, you know,
Wade Brown: Yeah, Brewbarry is just a walking arsenal, right?
David Mendenhall: From a practical standpoint, it's not money that's going to be shared with Vukradin, so it's effectively the same.
Kostadis Roussos: I see. So Vukradin is optimizing for a poverty lifestyle.
David Mendenhall: No! Do you know how much these sending stones are worth? It's practically rich at this point.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know for a fact they weren't stolen?
David Mendenhall: I was given assurances that they weren't.
Kostadis Roussos: I'd say we've already become directionless plus I thought you were gonna
David Mendenhall: Obtain those in a fair, honorable way.
Kostadis Roussos: So we don't do provenance here.
David Mendenhall: there's only so much you can do come on which wizard created them how did he obtain the spell components for casting this ascending spell
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, hold on.
natasha: I have a meme I need to share. It's for old people. You can read it out loud.
David Mendenhall: Wade's not old. I don't think he can care.
natasha: Tell me when you're done and give me the phone back.
Kostadis Roussos: Exercise for people over 60. Begin by standing on a comfortable surface where you have plenty of room on each time. With a 5 pound potato bag in each hand, extend your arms straight out from your sides and hold them there as long as you can. Try to reach a full minute, then relax. Each day you'll find that you can hold this position for just a bit longer. After a couple of weeks, move up to 10 pound potato bags.
Kostadis Roussos: Then try a 50-pound potato bag, and eventually work your way up to where you can lift a 100-pound potato bag in each hand and hold your arm straight out for more than a minute. I'm at this level. After you feel confident at this level, put a potato in each bag.
David Mendenhall: That was close.
Gary Young: This resonated.
Kostadis Roussos: Latasha said this resonated.
David Mendenhall: I heard.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
natasha: I can't find this funny.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay, so you show up here again and Dazlyn and Norbus are like, oh, you're back, you're back.
David Mendenhall: They didn't die trying to steal the gem?
Wade Brown: They didn't hear the broadcast or anything?
David Mendenhall: Are you sure they're not dead?
Kostadis Roussos: Did they do that? You told them where the-
David Mendenhall: Absolutely would have done that.
Kostadis Roussos: all right um no i'm just trying to see when they did that like you guys i'm just thinking like you guys went over there um they wouldn't have done it the same day when you came out they would have waked up in the morning you guys went out to the orcs the orcs attacked so they probably kind of hid here to see whether you're alive or dead Head.
Kostadis Roussos: Because, you know, what's the point of having a gem if the orcs are going to kill you? They're trying to decide whether they need to run, you know, whatever. They see you all come back, and Dazlyn and Norbus say, hmm, you're back.
David Mendenhall: We're going to camp for a while.
Kostadis Roussos: See, you're not here for the gem, right?
Gary Young: We're here to partake of your hospitality.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, ah, Dazlyn turns to Norbus, Norbus turns to Dazlyn. Well, let's go over here, and there's a nice little fire pit over here, and they say that they decide that it's an appropriate time to cook a pleasant meal.
David Mendenhall: Okay, that's not right.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Can I play my flute a little bit for that?
Kostadis Roussos: And it sounds like Vukradin made a, a new poem.
David Mendenhall: Yes. Oh. The orc slaughtered us, slaughtered us, slaughtered-
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, all right, so Vukradin, they, so the next day, that's the third. That's an average performance.
David Mendenhall: Performance, Not My Path.
Kostadis Roussos: Dazlyn was unimpressed. Norbist was pleased.
Wade Brown: Keep at it.
David Mendenhall: I'll take at it. I'll take at it.
Kostadis Roussos: Both of them were disappointed that you chose to play one of your own personal compositions instead of one of the more popular ditties of the area.
David Mendenhall: I'm sure they were. I've heard that a lot. I've gotten that a lot.
Kostadis Roussos: but you know all right are you guys gonna wait for them to go or just gonna leave
David Mendenhall: You mean we're, we long rested and then I think we can head out.
Kostadis Roussos: all right you're heading out all right yeah you're heading out all righty uh where is this Sword Coast all right you're at the dwarven exclamation
Gary Young: Back to Fanduano.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on.
Gary Young: I assume so. What's on our smith blog? What? What's on our-
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, there's, there's, uh, there were several quests.
David Mendenhall: there was another oh we have to get our 50 gp reward for this
Kostadis Roussos: So first, let's go get started.
David Mendenhall: Organic Fair Trade Gold
UNKNOWN: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: What level are you guys?
David Mendenhall: 1,
Wade Brown: One.
Kostadis Roussos: On your way back, as you're heading towards Phandalin, you hear an ogre whistling, whistling.
David Mendenhall: I should be able to recognize the song.
Kostadis Roussos: You should be able to harmonize Roll your performance Roll your... Alright All right.
David Mendenhall: Another 10. Not the best rolls.
Gary Young: 23 perception. I assume I know where this ogre is?
Kostadis Roussos: yes um he is he is uh coming up uh you're going on it's like hilly terrain so if you could imagine sort of a hill like this he's on that side and he's coming up so you guys can either try to meet him over there or try to sneak Necromancer,
David Mendenhall: Maybe I should ask your opinion this time. Is this a fellow musician?
Gary Young: He seems like he would be a slave, I mean that's normally what we would have done with Ogres and Menzoberranzan, at least he's one of these
David Mendenhall: Please free him then!
Gary Young: Friggin? I guess if that's the way you do these things on the surface.
David Mendenhall: All right, let's free the slaves!
Gary Young: Okay? Slave, you are-
David Mendenhall: That was not the outcome I expected, but let's try to freeze it.
Kostadis Roussos: Slave, you are free.
Wade Brown: I don't even know if he's a slave! Who jumped to that conclusion?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Hold on. I now need to set up an encounter. Give me a second. Um... Oh, man. I'm like, hey, here we go. Right. Uh... Is there any, like... Uh... Okay. So, I do not have...
Kostadis Roussos: I will have to do it this way. All right. There is a
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
David Mendenhall: Student.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Alright. Alright.
Gary Young: Good times.
Kostadis Roussos: all right okay so and
Wade Brown: So does he have any like bonds? Do we see any signs that he's actually a slave?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's definitely not a slave.
Wade Brown: He's just a wandering ogre.
Gary Young: 11 insight on Do. I think he's a surface ogre.
David Mendenhall: Surface ogre?
Gary Young: Is he a surface ogre or an underground ogre?
Wade Brown: He's on the surface.
Gary Young: He could have been, you know, like, when the demons invaded Menzoberranzan, you know, like, there's all kinds of people from the Underdark that, you know, made it to the surface.
Kostadis Roussos: Eleven. Is there such thing as an underground ogre? Ogres of the Underdark?
Gary Young: There were plenty of them in the slave pits and in the-
Kostadis Roussos: To be quite honest, since there isn't actually a difference between them, you can't tell.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: with that level of insight okay my higher level
David Mendenhall: I guess, I guess I would shout out at this point: Ogre, are you a musician or a slave?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: That would confuse anybody just whistling in the afternoon.
Gary Young: I hope you whistled the same song back to him.
David Mendenhall: Well, I tried, but I only got a 10 on my performance, so it wasn't so good.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, apparently ogres covet food and treasure and they spitefully destroy art.
Wade Brown: But he was whistling, that's making art!
David Mendenhall: Oh, slave!
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you called him the musician. He's like, me? Musician? Music? No. Me, Kelly? How dare you?
David Mendenhall: Wait, he doesn't like music? Oh, I'm definitely rolling for initiative now. 21. That's what you get for hating on music.
Wade Brown: Oh, this kid's gonna get us all killed.
David Mendenhall: All the blood money you'll get from killing him.
Wade Brown: I don't need blood money.
David Mendenhall: All right. Nice roll, Valphine. Yeah.
Wade Brown: You showed up, you're 21.
David Mendenhall: You did. She did.
Gary Young: All right.
David Mendenhall: We did very well on that one.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Alright, well, I will, uh, definitely attack. Alright, Valphine, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Mm-hmm. I call that.
Wade Brown: The white surface is all grassland or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Greslin.
Wade Brown: Lane, something like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Easy Terrain, that's the important thing. Moving between levels costs you, it makes it extra.
David Mendenhall: I don't plan on moving, so good to know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, like if you were to, going down costs you double movement, going up costs you double movement, and it's 10 feet. That's where the- So reason- Okay.
Gary Young: So I assume that, uh, your, your guide is set for five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, the battle has joined.
Gary Young: Ducksafe 13
David Mendenhall: Are we going to do 59 damage? This is going to be a process.
Kostadis Roussos: all right he takes four points of damage it's more damage yes does valphina stay within 30 feet which is his movement rate or does she take a few steps back to try to avoid being within his charge range Range.
Gary Young: Brewbarry is going to be in front.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that's Elfien's new strategy. All right, Rooker didn't, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Starry Wisp.
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
David Mendenhall: What's the two-hit on this ogre? 11, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: Ness.
David Mendenhall: That's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
Wade Brown: Damage
David Mendenhall: Eight Radio
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So eight points of damage.
David Mendenhall: The range is 60 feet, so I can definitely head back over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Who is next? Brewbarry.
David Mendenhall: Charge! Raid?
Kostadis Roussos: don't forget to rage remember he said he doesn't like music
Gary Young: Yeah, that's right.
David Mendenhall: Unbelievable.
Kostadis Roussos: I know. Okay, roll to hit.
Gary Young: Of course, I can't cleave, but, uh, well. Is that a miss? Oh, no, no, plus, plus two attack with the...
Kostadis Roussos: I only think it's for damage though.
Gary Young: Is it only damage?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Gary Young: I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: The change that
Gary Young: The abilities work.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm not expecting you. I'm kind of like, like, this is like, sort of like, I don't know. I'd like, I have to go read the new Plyer's Handbook. Hold on. Damage resistance. Rage damage. It's dis-damage. It's not to hit.
Gary Young: Advantage 1, Strength Change
David Mendenhall: Ignore that.
Gary Young: Yeah. Okay, just advantage on strength checks. So a 10 is a mess, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Alright then. But I'm not reaching.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All righty. Ogre. The ogre marches up to you and says, You left a square with my... Yeah, that is true. All right. A crit. Wow. Plus 4 points of damage.
David Mendenhall: You ranged, though, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so that's 19 plus 4 because you double the... Okay, he's down to 24. Damn! Halfway there! Alright, he's kind of like, damn!
David Mendenhall: That was impressive. Alright, the ogre is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, well done. Alright. That's ten points of damage, or five points of damage if you're raging.
Gary Young: Guess I'll take the five points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade Brown: Good call.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: all right we'll come on up a little closer and just cantrip away let's go poison spray uh that's a hit right he's 11. yeah
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, yep, that's a hit.
Wade Brown: 7 damage, taking him to 17.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. There's no poison condition related to poison spray, right?
Wade Brown: No, it's kind of weird, it just does 1d12 poison damage, that's it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: and Valtine. Valt was pretty nice.
Wade Brown: Yeah, it's a really nice cantrip.
David Mendenhall: Wow. It just does nothing. I don't have anything that does 1d12. That's awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
David Mendenhall: Dex save DC-13
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Ogres have really bad dexterity, so that is a good choice.
Gary Young: Stalag have options oh that's a crit on he got a natural plan all right
David Mendenhall: What's he down to? 17. 17 on the end of my turn.
Gary Young: Valkyrie
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming she stepped over here and then stepped over here. Luke or Dean, you're up. What did you just hit with? Starry Wisp? With Stranger?
David Mendenhall: Free Radio
Kostadis Roussos: You did that. All right. Only three?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, well, it's not a great damage roll.
Kostadis Roussos: is that another miss yeah you literally had a 25 chance to miss it's not that rare
David Mendenhall: Did somebody record the three damage?
Kostadis Roussos: No, could you please do that?
Wade Brown: Oh yeah, he's at 14 now.
David Mendenhall: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Brewbarry is done. Ogre is up. Alright. Yes, the Ogre is up. Ogre does 9. What is Brewbarry's animal class? No. Misses.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wow. Okay.
David Mendenhall: All right, Soma.
Wade Brown: Alright, hypothetically, I could thorn-whip him away from you, would you get an attack of opportunity?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you would.
Wade Brown: All right, let's do that. I'm going to come over here and just try to yank him away so you can get a free hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Wade Brown: Looks like that's pretty good.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so what does that do? Oh, you missed again.
Wade Brown: He takes 1d6 and I pull him 10 feet closer so I do have to pull him out of the way so move him like just move him one square over
Kostadis Roussos: 5, 10, that's 5 feet, that's 10 feet, all right, he's right next to you, and he's also not prone, right?
Wade Brown: It doesn't say anything about Prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, fine. Then he's a leaner. Alright, fine.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I was just trying to give me an attack. Oh well.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: We did record that's six damage, so there's another... he's at eight.
Gary Young: Yep. Valphine, you're up. Okay. I just do not die with this team. Sacred Flame might work this time.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, again, a good choice, this time it does work, and he takes 5 points of damage. Did someone apply it?
Wade Brown: No, he should be at three now.
Kostadis Roussos: These are the three. Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: I just... No, it's, uh, it's Vukradin. Yeah. That was at the bottom.
David Mendenhall: I'm gonna move my token a little bit and then
Kostadis Roussos: No, wait, hold on. Brewbarry just went, right?
Wade Brown: Now
Kostadis Roussos: I'll see you in the next one. Bye.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Valphine.
Wade Brown: Dalfini just went
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Soma just went, yeah, sorry.
Wade Brown: I did the Thorn Whip, but I missed this opportunity, Valphine did Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, I got it. I just got it.
Wade Brown: That's death if he dies, if he takes the whole damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he dies.
David Mendenhall: He is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Die, you anti-musician slave.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let's see what this treasure does he have.
Wade Brown: I had no idea you were so easily triggered.
David Mendenhall: I had to fight orcs, I had to fight an ogre, ogre jellies, this is not what I signed up for.
Gary Young: What did you sign up for?
David Mendenhall: Well, we were just supposed to go tell the dwarves that there was a dragon in the area and then go back to town.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you find walloping and ammunition on him.
Wade Brown: What?
David Mendenhall: No doubt stolen from another adventurer.
Kostadis Roussos: A creature hit by this by ammunition must succeed in a DC saving throw or have the prone condition.
Gary Young: Who has ranged weapons?
David Mendenhall: Not it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well...
David Mendenhall: You can always sell it.
Kostadis Roussos: all right all right okay um you find the walloping ammunition in a fortunately for you the the ogre did not know how to use it it's fortunate possibly because the ogre prefers just walloping people
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, the ogre is modus vivendi. All right. So you arrive in Phandalin.
Gary Young: So is there a reason that Valphine does not have a hand crossbow? I mean, she's a drow.
Kostadis Roussos: No, she can have a hand in crossbow.
David Mendenhall: I'd buy one.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I almost feel like a drow without a hand crossbow is kind of like not a real drow.
Gary Young: Yeah, seriously.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's sort of like, less of a drow. Um, alright, you arrive in the Town Master's Hall.
David Mendenhall: It is time to collect our reward.
Wade Brown: Our justly earned gold pieces.
David Mendenhall: Honorably Earned.
Kostadis Roussos: all right you show up at the uh let me just see there's one more all right see what happens i need to do something all right
Kostadis Roussos: So you arrive at the town master's hall, you knock on the door, and the door is again closed shut. Do you knock on the door? Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I want my money.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. He goes, if your voice again going, if you're a dragon, know that I'm far too thin and bony to make a good meal.
Wade Brown: Dragons aren't usually the type to knock.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade Brown: Sometimes
Kostadis Roussos: Right, you do remember that asking him about a quest, um, talking to him about a quest gets him to walk out of his room. So, you're asking about the quest. So, last time you, you asked him about a quest, he, uh, he stopped, like, he's not responding to you. You could be a trick, I don't know it for a fact that you're not the dragon, so just go away, I'm too skinny.
David Mendenhall: I'm sure
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: I got a 20 persuasion. I should be able to persuade him out the door.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I think I've heard your voice before. You're that bard that played in the Stonehill Inn.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that's me!
Kostadis Roussos: No? But I do recall, no. Sorry, should I remember you?
UNKNOWN: Let's play this.
David Mendenhall: Well, anyway, we came here for our money.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you came here for your money?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we told the dwarves about the dragon.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you told, oh excellent, excellent, excellent, I'm feeling very much happy, they're very charming people, you know.
David Mendenhall: They seemed kind of like grave robbers.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: You don't think?
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses and goes, what do you mean they think they're grave robbers?
David Mendenhall: Well, I mean, they were, you know, digging in a ruin for artifacts, and I don't think they were intended to put all those artifacts in a museum.
Kostadis Roussos: Hubbard goes, his lordship, Neverember, said that adventurers are allowed to seize and control whatever treasure they wish.
David Mendenhall: well that doesn't seem right at all anyway i will go with my typical diatribe
Kostadis Roussos: Harbin has this look if you do you want to roll your insight does anybody want to check their insight or investigation insight sure all right Valphine picks up that he is very unhappy with with uh morality yes
David Mendenhall: Did he pay me my 50 gold pieces?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes he did.
David Mendenhall: Alright, well that's all I really care about.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he is very upset with what he's heard.
David Mendenhall: You're upset with the orcs attacking the dwarves? You're upset with the fine, upstanding, moral citizen of Faerun?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, well, I mean, do you ask him about it?
David Mendenhall: No, I'm just surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, well, I'm just telling you, I'm just saying he seems very upset, anxious even.
David Mendenhall: Interesting. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. All right. So, there are the next set of quests. Harburn says, well, since you seem to be in the business of being a hero and don't want to take any more treasure, the good news is that I have plenty more quests for you.
Gary Young: Awesome!
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent. We seem to be having a shortage of adventures these days. Something about the dragon terrorizing everyone.
Gary Young: How about something other than Dragon?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I suppose I could get you something other than dragon. We always have... He turns to you. You won't have any real issue with the, um... Alright, he goes, alright, okay, so there's two more quests.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see whether I can have, let me see if they actually provided this.
David Mendenhall: Rock gnomes and the midwife.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Yes. They don't have the quest.
David Mendenhall: I think it was the gnomes paid better, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Icespire Hold, Neverember, Lionshield Coster, Vorga Long-Memory,
David Mendenhall: Alright, how about Gnomes?
Wade Brown: Ever the Starving Artist
Kostadis Roussos: I need more organic fair trade gold.
Gary Young: Um, uh, to the Lionshield Coster? Yeah.
David Mendenhall: What about the Sending Stones? Should we keep those or sell them off?
Kostadis Roussos: You're not going to have anybody to sell them off in this town.
David Mendenhall: Oh, interesting. Okay. Well, I guess we're keeping them then.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. In terms of the weapons, you can sell them to the smithy. He'll be happy. He'll be happy for half price.
Gary Young: for half price.
Kostadis Roussos: They're damaged.
Gary Young: Half price, not 90% price?
Kostadis Roussos: No, Half-Price, they're damaged.
Gary Young: Okay, so...
Kostadis Roussos: they were damaged sorry yes i don't know if i if i didn't say that that's my my bad
Wade Brown: I feel like you did.
Kostadis Roussos: I think I did.
Gary Young: Okay, it's fine. And same with the Heidermar.
Kostadis Roussos: The Height Armor is in fine shape. You can sell that to Lionshield Coaster for what is just one step above Leather Armor.
Gary Young: Yeah, it's normally worth 10 gold, so.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you can sell it for 10 gold.
David Mendenhall: For nine, I assume, because we have it. Yes, yes, yes, yep. And the jeweled dagger, and the gemstones.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, who do you sell those to? Barthen's Provisions? Tell us. Let me just see. Hold on.
Gary Young: The jewel backer might go to the blacksmith, you might find that interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, I'm trying to see something, there it is, Ventolin, I'm sure, there we go, that's what I was looking for.
Wade Brown: I'll be back in a moment.
Kostadis Roussos: all right okay all right okay so fine all right so you you go to the so while you're going uh to the various stores to the smithy to Lionshield Coster um when you get to the Lionshield Coster store Store.
Kostadis Roussos: Lineny, uh, she tells, she says, oh, you're still alive.
Gary Young: This time.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, excellent, excellent.
David Mendenhall: and several near-death experiences. It's a new thing for me. I've never had this happen before.
Gary Young: The pain was glorious.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you awkward. She goes, well, as you know, ever since the Lionshield Coster used to have a big business, unfortunately, there were things that happened that have made our business not as able to provide all the goods that people would like, but we're still in business.
Gary Young: What has disrupted your trade?
Kostadis Roussos: You know, that's sort of an in-business. Supply chains, so it's all very technical.
Gary Young: Crafts.
David Mendenhall: There it is.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Tariff Search, that's it.
Gary Young: Those are purple tariffs, got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Tariffs, Disruptions, Market Force Dynamics.
David Mendenhall: Do you need any help with that? She looks at you and says, well... Do you have a shipment that you need us to go procure for you, or transport you poorly, or can we offer our services?
Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
David Mendenhall: That would be a fair and honorable way for us to earn money.
Kostadis Roussos: oh oh that's what you meant i thought you meant to actually solve my problem of the oh ah oh uh yes but not today i'm not expecting a shipment
David Mendenhall: Was there another problem you needed help with?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, actually, not really, but I did hear a rumor.
Gary Young: What's the rumor?
Kostadis Roussos: Strange magic pervades Neverwinter Wood, confounding navigators and obscuring the ancient ruins of bygone kingdoms lost in its depths. Here, I'll cut and paste it. I cut and paste it into the chat. I put it in the off-striker.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, and so she says, will you be staying at the Stonehill Inn?
Gary Young: Yeah I suppose so. I mean what time is it?
David Mendenhall: I guess we do have the money for that now, that's amazing. Treat yourself.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, yeah, you know, it's like the Stonehill Inn is gonna be open for business.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you arrive at the Stonehill Inn, and Toblen, the Stonehill Inn tavern keeper, is very happy to see you, and he says, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, it's so wonderful to see you.
Gary Young: Yes, wonderful to see you too.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, hold on, is it? What? Did you say-
Gary Young: Wonderful to see you too. Beer?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, excellent, yes, beer.
Gary Young: Beer. Song.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, well, I can't do song, but if I recall correctly, your friend here does an excellent song.
David Mendenhall: Do you have a piano?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I still haven't bought a piano.
David Mendenhall: So flute or clarinet then?
Kostadis Roussos: Are you asking if I have any of those interested ones?
David Mendenhall: No, no, no, I have one. Which would you prefer? I'm happy to play.
Kostadis Roussos: Flute or Clarinet? Well, whichever one you prefer. Clarinet.
David Mendenhall: Thank you, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Myronet.
David Mendenhall: I assume you want one of your pop numbers.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, if I recall correctly, you were doing something that you did that was very, very good.
David Mendenhall: Okay, an average
Kostadis Roussos: Good Music
Wade Brown: What's with your plus 5 never hitting above like 20?
David Mendenhall: I don't know, I've been rolling badly tonight.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay.
David Mendenhall: Where's my 25 performance? I want that.
Kostadis Roussos: all right um so he goes okay that won't work
Kostadis Roussos: So all right so there's a few more people in the town in the the inn um you can ask if they have any more um if they've heard any more rumors or you can go spend the night sleeping Sleeping.
David Mendenhall: Go ahead guys, I'm just playing the flute.
Gary Young: I guess Valsminae will check the mood of the crowd because, you know, everyone loves a drow asking questions.
Wade Brown: Nothing sus about that.
David Mendenhall: Totally normal, completely fair, yeah, it'd be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, so, so, roll your perception, or investigation, roll your insider investigation.
Gary Young: All right. Insight.
David Mendenhall: Now you're plus-fiving at average.
Gary Young: So with all my attack rolls with plus five and then this one with plus five.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, um, quite honestly, you know, you can't really tell.
David Mendenhall: Thelma, you wanna take a, take a, take a try? Oh, sure. How about Brewbarry?
Gary Young: No, he specifically sings the music.
David Mendenhall: I mean I have a minus one of course there you go oh yeah lovely jesus christ guys
Gary Young: Okay, so we just have our existing quests, I guess that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: So you're not going to ask anybody?
David Mendenhall: No, we did.
Gary Young: We done.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I thought he was, like, doing an investigation to see if anybody, whatever... He was. He was. You should see his rolls. Oh, good grief. Did I miss something really funny?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, I was trying to come up with rumors and frantically going through my DMG guide.
Gary Young: No, you don't need to bother with that.
David Mendenhall: We didn't roll well enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't worry. All right. Okay. All right. Okay. So the next morning, and off to Gnomengarde, right?
David Mendenhall: Why'd that cost us the gold?
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't actually say that.
David Mendenhall: I assume the town's not, the inn's not free, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I just realized that.
David Mendenhall: One gold, that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: one gold yeah let's just make it one gold all right so um off to gnomengarde where is this yeah ah i didn't put you on the right map all right here we go gnomengarde so you go through do you want to go through the hilly terrain go to the grasslands or just head
Kostadis Roussos: Slink. How do you want to go?
Wade Brown: which direction is it oh it's more of an activation no wait that's not okay
Gary Young: Hold on, sorry, sorry, I just realized.
David Mendenhall: Where is that?
Gary Young: Valphine would like to go through the most brightly lit path possible.
David Mendenhall: Just go straight.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, through the hilly terrain, through the, um, alright. How else?
Gary Young: Pesky tree cover, I need to have this sun.
David Mendenhall: Ten miles.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, no, it's 15 miles.
Gary Young: I just thought you were allergic to the sun. No, no, the sun is gloriously painful.
Kostadis Roussos: yeah you're not really understanding like like the whole uh Valphine Valphine thing um
David Mendenhall: What do we have to do with the Gnomes? Let me look. Remind me. How quickly can we get this done? Gnomes are known for their magical inventions. They might have something to do with the Feet of the Dragon. Get whatever you can from them. So we just need to trade with the Gnomes. Okay. That's fast. We can trade very quickly.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Wade Brown: Holding on.
David Mendenhall: Holding on. Holding on. We can get whatever we can. We might be able to get nothing, and then we've gotten whatever we can, and we get our 50 gold pieces.
Wade Brown: Technically correct. The best kind of correct.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold that, here, one second. Alright, oh, let's just do it this way.
David Mendenhall: Vacuous Troop.
Kostadis Roussos: So as you're going through, so imagine this is a, you're going through the mountains, right, as you turn around the corner, so imagine this is a mountain pass kind of thing,
Kostadis Roussos: A ogre is standing in the middle of the way.
David Mendenhall: Other Ogre
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Well, Valphine, is this one a slave too?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me check.
Wade Brown: Is it whistling?
Gary Young: XIV.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's definitely, oh, not a slave.
Gary Young: Cause usually when they're slaves they don't whistle cheerfully.
David Mendenhall: Oh, he just wants to kill us, then. Like the other one. It seems like everybody out here just wants to kill us.
Kostadis Roussos: The Ogre goes, I hungry, I eat you.
David Mendenhall: We have food. Can we just give you some food and you can stand over there because we're just walking past you.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks. I like turtle.
Wade Brown: Excuse me?
David Mendenhall: I don't have any turtle, I have some rations.
Kostadis Roussos: Turtle. I eat turtle.
Wade Brown: No. No eat turtle.
Kostadis Roussos: Do we have something else to feed him?
David Mendenhall: Anybody?
Kostadis Roussos: So you're going to have to try, if you want to persuade him, you're going to have to intimidate him.
Wade Brown: Intimidate an ogre?
David Mendenhall: You could try that. It's not happening. Not usually my style, but let's see what happens. Nope. Nope. Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: You do not succeed in intimidating.
David Mendenhall: Do you want to try intimidation?
Kostadis Roussos: and a few more.
David Mendenhall: Valphine, you gotta roll. See if you can get under us.
Kostadis Roussos: Did I?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we got it right. Excellent. Well done, guys. Well done.
Wade Brown: I told you, don't intimidate ogres!
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, I don't think the ogre was intimidated.
David Mendenhall: We know. We know.
Kostadis Roussos: In fact, I think the ogre now is excited because he saw your attempted intimidation and thinks this is going to be an easy, he goes, I, eternal elf.
David Mendenhall: I've killed other ogres like you.
Wade Brown: Just yesterday we took out one of your brothers.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, did you say that?
David Mendenhall: We should get a plus two. Yeah, I would say that. I'm getting kind of ticked off.
Wade Brown: Let everyone kill me. Yeah, let everyone cry and say it.
David Mendenhall: All I ever wanted to do was play music.
Kostadis Roussos: You killed my brother!
David Mendenhall: I love it.
Kostadis Roussos: it's a free rage all right it enrages him
Wade Brown: Nice going, kiddo. You just ticked him off.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, let me just put an ogre in the combat tracker.
Wade Brown: Another one.
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, it's, you know, it's like what you encounter on the module.
David Mendenhall: No, it's fine, it's fine. Alright, well, I'm gonna have to stop, I think.
Kostadis Roussos: Will we stop at the end of this?
David Mendenhall: I'm going to try some different spells. I've got some other ideas.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry
Kostadis Roussos: Valphine and Brewbarry, you need to put your mission rules.
Gary Young: 11 and 9.
UNKNOWN: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: all right okay okay all right all right Soma you're up
Wade Brown: Oh man, I'm first. How did that happen?
Kostadis Roussos: So just to give you an idea, right? You're in the middle of a sort of a valley with the
Wade Brown: Yeah, no, I was wondering if I could just, like, mold earths and rocks on top of them or something. Uh... Uh... I mean, he's literally surrounded.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I'm just trying to, I'm actually saying yes, but I just don't know how to measure the damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah, does this actually have a roll? What happens when I roll? Oh, it just does that.
Gary Young: You can just roll cantrip damage if you want to make it easy.
Wade Brown: Well, you know, I like the idea.
David Mendenhall: And it would be, it would be like the dirt that's above him, you would loosen it and then it would fall on him. Yeah. Especially from quite high up.
Wade Brown: I could make a good rock slide or something onto him, you know, like, we make a big old, basically like a rock avalanche come down on him or something.
David Mendenhall: It says this movement doesn't have enough force to cause damage.
Wade Brown: Well, yeah, but from up above, that potential energy gets converted into damage, like dropping a penny off the Empire State Building.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Can that kill you?
Wade Brown: I don't think it can, but that's just because pennies have a very low terminal velocity.
David Mendenhall: and
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright, alright, alright. So I will declare that it would cause 1d6 worth of damage.
Wade Brown: Alright, we'll just poison spray him.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Screw being creative. Good old poison spray. Nothing beats it.
Kostadis Roussos: No, yeah, unfortunately the mold earth spell, the problem with it-
Wade Brown: It's fine. It's not meant for damage. I just kind of wanted to screw around. So I'll just do it.
Kostadis Roussos: You could have used it to make the terrain difficult so he can't charge at you.
Wade Brown: Yeah, but that also makes it hard for Brewbarry to get in there.
David Mendenhall: I have better ideas on that. All right, eight damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah, 51. And I'm actually going to scoot back since he said turtle was sort of his favorite food.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, unfortunately he made it.
David Mendenhall: Put me in front. Thanks, dude.
Wade Brown: you're the one who pissed him off this is uh the spray doesn't have a saving throw
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, it's a hit. Oh, it's a hit, right? Sorry, my bad.
Wade Brown: Yeah, he just takes 8 damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes
Wade Brown: Question.
David Mendenhall: All right, ogre's up.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Ogre's like...
Wade Brown: All righty
David Mendenhall: I taste bad, don't come after me!
Kostadis Roussos: No, hold on.
Gary Young: Our turn order leaves something to be desired.
David Mendenhall: yeah our marching order was not marching order
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think that would be... He would be here.
David Mendenhall: I think I would be in the back I'm gonna be in the back I don't think that looks more sane Zane.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I can't imagine that would have been your order.
Gary Young: Oh, he exited a square that I'm threatening.
David Mendenhall: no that's right ogre ogre is up first
Gary Young: Yeah, but I still get my reaction on him.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, you take four points of damage.
Gary Young: I'll get it.
Wade Brown: Don't forget to rage!
Kostadis Roussos: he doesn't get to rage up until it he gets to rage on his turn not it's all right so the ogre uh swings his axe uh and rolls a one
David Mendenhall: That's amazing.
Kostadis Roussos: Cuts off his own toe. Valphine. Valphine.
Gary Young: Oh. Hmm. I guess they would have a high strength save, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: I can walk in this dark grey.
Kostadis Roussos: yes uh just every time you go on it it's counts as 10 feet of movement going going up on it costs you 10 and so you can then move normally on it
Gary Young: So I moved 28, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Okay, and I'll just use my mace.
Kostadis Roussos: you can't then you have to go back down so you'd have to go through
David Mendenhall: Missed, anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just saying you might want to use your spell. That's what I'm trying to say.
Gary Young: Okay, I will use my spell instead.
Kostadis Roussos: Or a ranged weapon. That's where your choices are.
Gary Young: Well, maybe we should try this new hand crossbow.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, try the new hand crossbow. Gosh darn it, that is a hit. Are you using one of the special bullets or you're just using it for damage?
Gary Young: Roll a strength save dc 10?
David Mendenhall: You should be able to make that.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't!
David Mendenhall: What's your plus on strength size?
Kostadis Roussos: and more.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay. All right. He's prone then.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's prone.
David Mendenhall: And he takes 3 damage.
Gary Young: Uh-huh.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Did you get the damage?
Gary Young: You got it.
David Mendenhall: Use a Baldur's Gate 3 standby.
Kostadis Roussos: What was that?
David Mendenhall: make a dc3 dc13 wisdom save
Kostadis Roussos: Bluzzit
David Mendenhall: is halted and can take no actions until the end of his next turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, well, well.
David Mendenhall: Nor can he move.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: Brewbarry. Alright, so he is prone, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. And halted. So that is 12 points of damage.
Gary Young: Uh, with, with, uh- points plus two rage, so 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'll get, I got that. You got that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Back to the top of the order is me.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Or, okay, let's just do you, Soma, and we'll stop after that because it's 10:30.
Wade Brown: Yeah. I think I'm still best off just doing poison spray, right? Just hit it. Hit it and get out.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh boy, another 4 damage.
Wade Brown: Right.
Gary Young: Okay, and we will stop here.
David Mendenhall: Should we just do the ogre's turn, which is to be skipped? To do nothing, and then remove the halt condition.
Kostadis Roussos: He's still prone.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Valphine starts next week.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, excellent. Okay, next week we will not be playing because I will be in Greece, probably hopelessly inebriated at this time, recovering from my inebriation.
David Mendenhall: Well, at this time in Greece, it'll be 730 in the morning. You're going to be drunk at 730 in the morning?
Kostadis Roussos: or Recovering.
David Mendenhall: Not sure which, one or the other.
Kostadis Roussos: Just a logical OR here.
Wade Brown: There will be alcohol. There'll be blood in your alcohol system.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. So I don't think I'll be able to be awake. All right, guys, take care.
David Mendenhall: Bye-bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye. Bye.